This program allows users to upload multiple fMRI images at once and predict gestational age based on head circumference.
Now, please open the source code repository for fetal age prediction
and click on the 'Open In Colab' button.
Confirm that the runtime type is set to Python 3 and GPU hardware acceleration is enabled.
Run all
Run anyway
Click the Files icon on the left.
Click the Upload to session storage icon above.
Select and upload local fMRI files.
You can also drag and drop files directly from the File Explorer.
After all files have been uploaded,
Press Enter in the input box
to continue executing the program
Install MONAI
Download the VNet model parameters.
Shortly, you will be able to observe the predicted gestational age data based on each fMRI file.
Next, I will provide a detailed explanation of the method for predicting gestational age from a single fMRI file.
Firstly, disconnect and delete
the current runtime environment.
Release the code of Debug.
Run all.
Upload an fMRI file.
Press Enter to continue.
Please be patient and wait
for approximately half a minute.
Based on the number of 3D
fetal brain images within the fMRI,
you will observe multiple output images.
The AI model processes the mask directly to obtain measurement data.
The list displays AI measured FOD/BPD/HC for each fetal brain image within the fMRI, along with the predicted GA result.
You can select the median by sorting the numerical values in the list.
The longer and shorter sides of the yellow rectangle represent FOD and BPD, respectively.
The red circles represent head
circumference (HC) measurements.
I believe you have noticed that the yellow border may not align perfectly with the axis of the fetal brain section.
However, upon observing the measurement values in the list,
you will notice minimal variance, especially in HC values.
Moreover, you can selectively choose suitable measurement values
and replace the source code with your preferred empirical formula.
Wishing you a pleasant coding experience!